<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Security on The Hidden Port</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on The Hidden Port</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.146.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thehiddenport.dev/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Amazon GuardDuty: Setup, Findings, and SIEM Integration</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-guardduty-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-guardduty-setup/</guid><description>Learn how to enable Amazon GuardDuty, understand its security findings, and integrate with SIEM solutions for enhanced threat detection in AWS.</description></item><item><title>Detecting Privilege Escalation in AWS Using CloudTrail and EventBridge</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-detecting-privilege-escalation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-detecting-privilege-escalation/</guid><description>Learn how to detect IAM privilege escalation attempts in AWS using CloudTrail logs, EventBridge rules, and practical detection engineering strategies. Includes examples, alerting techniques, and real-world API call patterns.</description></item><item><title>Building a Hardened Amazon Linux 2 AMI for Secure EC2 Deployments</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ami-hardening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ami-hardening/</guid><description>Learn how to create a hardened, compliant Amazon Linux 2 AMI using EC2 Image Builder with CIS benchmarks, security tools, and automation for production-ready AWS environments.</description></item><item><title>Enforcing Least Privilege in AWS IAM with Access Analyzer and Last Access Data</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-enforcing-least-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-enforcing-least-privilege/</guid><description>A practical guide on enforcing least privilege in AWS IAM by using IAM Access Analyzer and service Last Accessed data. Includes real workflows, auditing strategies, and automation tips.</description></item><item><title>Securing EC2 Access with AWS Systems Manager Session Manager: Eliminating SSH</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-securing-ec2-access-with-ssm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-securing-ec2-access-with-ssm/</guid><description>A comprehensive guide to replacing SSH access with AWS Systems Manager Session Manager for EC2 instances, enhancing security and compliance.</description></item><item><title>Hardening EC2 Instances for AWS Security: A Practical Guide</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ec2-hardening/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ec2-hardening/</guid><description>Learn how to harden EC2 instances in AWS using step-by-step technical guidance. Covers IAM, OS hardening, monitoring, encryption, and AWS best practices.</description></item><item><title>I Built an AWS Incident Response Toolkit (and You Can Use It)</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ir-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/aws-ir-toolkit/</guid><description>After publishing my free AWS IR checklist, I decided to go one step further — a full incident response toolkit with Terraform code, automation scripts, and ready-to-use templates. Here’s what’s inside.</description></item><item><title>Building Least-Privilege IAM Roles with IAM Access Analyzer</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/iam-access-analyzer-least-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/iam-access-analyzer-least-privilege/</guid><description>Learn how to use IAM Access Analyzer to identify risky permissions, generate fine-tuned IAM policies, and integrate the tool into your AWS development workflow.</description></item><item><title>How to Detect AWS Root Account Usage (And Respond to It)</title><link>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/detect-root-account-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thehiddenport.dev/posts/detect-root-account-usage/</guid><description>This guide walks you through detecting and responding to AWS root account usage using CloudTrail, EventBridge, SNS, and optionally Lambda or Slack. Includes Terraform examples and AWS Console workflows.</description></item></channel></rss>